(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
今日は僕だって！アイドル
Today, I'm an idol too!
猫又おかゆ生誕祭2022
Nekomata Okayu Birthday Festival 2022
p.h.
作詞・作曲：SEVENTHLINKS
Lyrics & Composition: SEVENTHLINKS
心臓に傷を負った
My heart has been wounded
言えない 言えない 黒い傷
A black wound I can't speak of
涙が溢れ出して止まらない
Tears overflow and won't stop
早く止血剤をくれ！
Quick, give me a hemostat!
無意味な液体を流し込む
Pouring in a meaningless liquid
化学反応で発作が起こって
A chemical reaction triggers a seizure
あいつの身体は重傷になって
His body is seriously injured
どうやら手遅れのようだ
It seems it's already too late
亡命している している している
In exile, in exile, in exile
亡命している している 生命を
In exile, in exile, my very life
蹂躙している している している
Trampled, trampled, trampled
蹂躙している している
Trampled, trampled
幸福に浸って帰らぬ医療廃棄物となった
Immersed in bliss, turned into medical waste
注射器にキスをした
Kissed the syringe
冥土界は冷静に笑った
The underworld laughed calmly
p.h.って胃酸を沢山吐いていて
p.h. means vomiting lots of stomach acid
体内は空
The inside of the body is empty
高尚な志に支配された
Dominated by noble aspirations
拙い拙い自慰行為
Clumsy, clumsy self-gratification
所謂ハッピーエンドじゃないか
Isn't it a so-called happy ending?
実世界では生きていけない
I can't live in the real world
流行の病に
To the fashionable disease
流行りの病に罹っ...
Falling for a popular disease...
...って脳味噌共々呉れてやる
...I'll give it all to you along with my brains.
悪い自意識の塊を以て
With a mass of bad self-consciousness,
貴方の血肉に成れるなら
If I could become your flesh and blood.
溶解している している している
Melting, melting, melting.
平衡は 相殺している している している
Equilibrium is canceling out, canceling out, canceling out.
a と a が混ざり合って 自己乖離定数を満たした
a and a mix together, satisfying the self-dissociation constant.
チュ チュ チュ 注射と ハ ハ ハ ハグを
Chu chu chu, an injection and a ha ha ha hug,
した め め め 冥界で 生命は咲き...
We did it, in the underworld, life bloomed...
...った ぺ ぺ ぺ p.h. って 涎を綺麗に拭いている
...d. Pe pe pe, p.h., wiping the drool clean.
タ タ タ 体内を食う
Ta ta ta, eating my inside.
チュ チュ チュ 注射と キ キ キ キスを
Chu chu chu, an injection and a ki ki ki kiss,
した め め め 冥界は 冷静に笑った
We did it, the underworld laughed calmly.
ぺ ぺ ぺ p.h. って 胃酸を沢山吐いている
Pe pe pe, p.h., vomiting a lot of stomach acid.
タ タ タ 体内は空
Ta ta ta, the inside is empty.
絶望は幸福になって
Despair becomes happiness,
空想は実在になって
Fantasy becomes reality,
錆び切った感覚は 中和している
The rusty senses are neutralizing.
生活は残骸になって
Life becomes wreckage,
正常は感冒になって
Normality becomes a common cold,
腐り尽くした吐瀉物で 乾杯をした
With rotten vomit, we made a toast.
はぁ〜 はぁ...
Haa... haa...
ちょっと休憩...
A little break...
よいしょ...
Up we go...
はい、ということで皆さん、どうもこんばんは！
Alright, so everyone, good evening!
ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆです。
I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers.
今日は僕の誕生日なんだけど...
Today is my birthday, but...
ちょっと疲れたんでね、横にならせてください。
I'm a bit tired, so let me lie down for a moment.
はぁ〜...
Haa...
えーと、あ、そうそう！
Umm, oh, that's right!
今日に向けて僕めっちゃね、ダンスとか練習してきて
I practiced dancing and stuff a lot for today,
頑張って、頑張って覚えてきたから
and worked hard, worked hard to memorize it,
みんなにめっちゃ楽しみにしててほしいんだよね。
so I want everyone to really look forward to it.
でもこの後もめっちゃ頑張るけど、ちょっと一回休憩させて。
I'll work really hard after this too, but let me rest for just a bit.
あ、でもね、今日は配信最後まで見ててほしいんだよね。
Ah, but you know, I want you to watch the stream until the very end today.
僕の誕生日をお祝いしてほしいっていうのもあるけど...
There's the part about wanting you to celebrate my birthday, but...
あの、最後の方で、みんなが喜ぶような告知があったりとかあるからね。
well, towards the end, there might be an announcement that will make everyone happy.
まあ僕ね、最近作詞勉強とかしてたんで、
Well, I've been studying songwriting lately,
ま、何がとは言わないけど、何がとは言わないけど、作詞勉強してたんだよね。
so, I won't say what for, I won't say what for, but I was studying songwriting.
で、今一番最初に歌った『p.h.』っていう曲は、
And the song I just sang first, 'p.h.',
僕がもうすごい大好きで、歌ってみたの動画もね、出したりとかしてるんだけど
I really love it, and I've even released a cover video of it,
踊りもすごい大好きだったから、踊ってみたいなって思ってたんで、
but I also really loved the dance, and I wanted to try dancing it,
ちょっとその夢を叶えちゃいました。えへへへへ。
so I went ahead and made that dream come true. Ehehehe.
ちょっと疲れたけど、まあ次、あの、あ、ゲストもね、いっぱい来てくださってるんで、
I'm a bit tired, but next, well, ah, many guests are coming today,
よいしょ、よいしょ...
Heave-ho...
ゲストのみんなの所に行こうと思います！
so I think I'll go to where the guests are!
じゃあみんな、さらばー！
Well then everyone, farewell!
触れてみたい秘密と 壊してたい夜の中で
In the secrets I want to touch and the nights I want to break,
間違いだらけの遊びしようよ
Let's play a game full of mistakes.
別に意味とか無いけどさ 眠い目を擦る
It doesn't really have a meaning, but I rub my sleepy eyes.
あれ？待ち合わせは何時？
Oh? What time was the meeting?
君はまだ履き違えてる また間違えてる
You're still misunderstanding, making mistakes again.
それで？貴方は誰なの？
So? Who are you?
こうして居たい居たいのは お互い様
Wanting to stay like this is mutual.
目が合う度に名前は呼ばないで
Don't call my name every time our eyes meet.
どうやったって見たいの隠さないから
Because I won't hide how I want to see you no matter what.
私のフリした私で良ければどうぞ
If a 'me' pretending to be 'me' is fine with you, then please.
塞ぐ目に落ちる景色の様に
Like the scenery falling into closing eyes,
霞む私は誰のものでもないの
The hazy me belongs to no one.
By me, so cynical からかわないで
By me, so cynical, don't tease me.
私だけに見せて 歪な夜をどうぞ
Show it only to me, an irregular night, please.
あーもう本当うざったい嫌嫌
Ah, it's really annoying now, no no.
何処かの誰かと赤の信号渡るよ いいでしょ？
I'll cross a red light with someone somewhere, okay?
ダメってダメって分かるでしょ？青に染まってたんじゃつまんない嫌嫌
You know 'no' means 'no', right? It's boring to be dyed in blue, no no.
何処か誰かと赤の信号渡るよ いいでしょ？
I'll cross a red light with someone somewhere, okay?
ダメって分かるでしょ？
You know that's no good, right?
青に染まっちゃってんじゃ
When you're dyed in blue...
つまんないや
...it's just boring.
ドクドク流れるテロップ
The ticker flows thumping along
交わす言葉に絡めるシロップ
With syrup mixed into our exchanged words
早くドキドキさせてよほら
Come on, make my heart race quickly
奔放する誰かと私のエゴ
The ego of someone acting out and mine
つまんないわ
It's so boring
いつもの様に
Just like usual
騙し騙され重なる狂気
Deceiving and being deceived, madness stacks up
ゆらり様に無情に
Swaying heartlessly
後はただ落ちるだけ
After that, we just fall
触れてみたい秘密と
With secrets I want to touch
壊してみたい夜の中で
Inside a night I want to break
間違いを繰り返して
Repeating our mistakes
触れてみたい秘密を
The secrets I want to touch
壊して知る夜の味を
Knowing the taste of the night by breaking them
戻れない初めましてをどうぞ
Here's a "nice to meet you" from which there's no return
塞ぐ目に落ちる景色の様に
Like the scenery falling upon closed eyes
霞む私は誰のものでもないの
I, becoming hazy, belong to no one
buy me そっぴり揶揄わないで
Buy me, don't tease me even a little bit
私だけに見せて
Show it only to me
歪な夜をどうぞ
Here is a warped night for you
塞ぐ目に落ちる景色の様に
Like the scenery falling upon closed eyes
霞む私は誰のものでもないの
I, becoming hazy, belong to no one
buy me そっぴり揶揄わないで
Buy me, don't tease me even a little bit
私だけに見せて
Show it only to me
秘密の夜をどうぞ
Here is a secret night for you
トワ様ー！
Towa-sama!
おかゆー！
Okayu!
おめでとうー！
Congratulations!
ありがとうトワー！
Thank you, Towa!
トワが歌ってるから気付かなかったけど、そんなテンション高かった！？
I didn't notice while Towa was singing, but was your energy that high!?
いや、歌う時はちょっとカッコつけて歌うけど！
Well, when I sing, I try to act a bit cool!
まぁ本当におめでとうの気持ちなんだけど、もうこういう事よ！
Well, I really wanted to celebrate, so this is just how I am!
ああ、嬉しいやん！
Aw, that makes me happy!
嬉しい。今めっちゃ嬉しかったよ。
I'm happy. I was really happy just now.
いやでも、僕さ、トワの誕生日とかに出させてもらってたから...
But you see, since I've appeared at your birthday and such...
今日は僕の誕生日にトワが祝いに来てくれたら嬉しいなって思ってたの。
I was hoping that Towa would come celebrate my birthday today.
いや、でもさ、トワ今回違うなと思ったのが...
But, you know, I thought Towa was different this time...
トワの生誕祭とか記念配信は、あの、二人で歌う事はなかったじゃん。
At your birthday festivals or anniversary streams, we never sang as a duo.
まぁ三人とかはあったけどね。
Well, we've done trios and such.
そうそうそう。二人で歌ったのは、あの家でゲラゲラ...
Right, right. The only time we sang as a duo was while laughing our heads off at home...
僕さ、今日自分の誕生日のライブにトワを呼ぶ事に一つ心配があって。
I actually had one concern about inviting Towa to my birthday live today.
何？
What?
トワと歌うと笑っちゃうから、その、歌い切れるかなっていう心配があったんだけど。
I was worried if I could finish the song because I always end up laughing when I sing with Towa.
歌ってるトワはやっぱりカッコいいし、踊ってるトワもカッコいいから...
But Towa singing is cool after all, and Towa dancing is cool too, so...
今日は笑わずに完走できたよね。
I was able to finish today without laughing.
いやでも、あの、まぁ確かに歌はちゃんと歌えたけど、その前めっちゃゲラゲラ笑ってたじゃん！
Wait, but, I mean sure, we sang properly, but you were laughing like crazy just before that!
「はい、やりましょう」の前！
Right before we said, "Okay, let's do this!"
そうだね。
That's true.
いや、でもさ、今日トワ気付いてたか分かんないけど...
But, I don't know if you noticed today, Towa...
僕、トワの歌い方を今日ちょっと寄せて歌ってみたんだけど気付いた？
I tried to sing a bit like you today, did you notice?
いや、カッコよかったわ！
Man, it was so cool!
本当！？
Really!?
めっちゃ良かったよ。
It was really good.
やっぱだから歌出そう。
That's why we should release a song.
え、何！？
Eh, what!?
歌出そう。
Let's release a song.
「出そう出そう」ってずっとまだ出してないから！
You keep saying "let's do it" but we still haven't!
いや、じゃあ出そう。今年はさ。
Well, let's do it then. This year.
出そう。
Let's do it.
じゃあ皆さん、出します！
So everyone, we're going to release one!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
ダーリンダンス
Darling Dance
存在証明 愛だって愛だって吐いたって
Proof of existence, even if I spit out "it's love, it's love"
嗚呼 ゴロンゴロンでやんや プリティプリティ ダイエットDAY
Ah, rolling around, yanya, Pretty Pretty Diet DAY
曖昧 一回楽に 曖昧 二回楽に
Ambiguous, once easily; ambiguous, twice easily
病み悪化してんだった 愛だ恋だ何だってんだ
My sickness was getting worse; love, romance, whatever it is
生命線は 愛だって愛だ 嘆いたって
The lifeline is "it's love, it's love," even if I lament
ああでもない こうでもないな 淋しい淋しいナンセンスDAY
Not this, not that; lonely, lonely nonsense DAY
いっそ密会 ラフに 節操無い解 LOVE ME
Might as well have a secret meeting, roughly; unprincipled answer, LOVE ME
踊れ踊れ 踊れ踊れ
Dance, dance; dance, dance
なにもない なにもない 私なにもない
Nothing, nothing, I have nothing
変われない 変われない 私変われない
Can't change, can't change, I can't change
分からない 分からない わかる分からない
Don't know, don't know, I understand I don't know
はーい 目もと以外は隠して
Yes! Hide everything except the eyes
ダダダダ ダリンダリンダリン ファニー
Da-da-da-da Darling, Darling, Darling, Funny
はい 冴えない愛情論でおねだり
Yes! Begging with a dull theory of love
ダーリン
Darling
ダダダダ　ダーリン脳裏
Da-da-da-da, darling, in my mind
DIRTY & DIRTY
会いたい衝動　埋めてよ
Bury the urge to meet you
ダダダダ
Da-da-da-da
ナナナナナナナナ
Na-na-na-na-na-na-na
無い無い情緒　感情が行ったり来たり
No, no emotions; feelings come and go
ナナナナナナナナナナ
Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na
無い無い情緒　感傷でダダダダ
No, no emotions; da-da-da-da with sentiment
（チュッ）
(Kiss sound)
ダダダダダーリン　愛だ、愛だって
Da-da-da-da darling, it's love, they say
まあ
Well
ゴロン　ニャン　食い意地　食い意地ダイエットDAY
Rolling around, meow, gluttony, gluttony diet day
もう精一杯で積み
Already at my limit, it's a mess
ボロ世界で無理
Impossible in this worn-out world
病み明かしてんだって　承認　承認　接待だ
I'm staying up sick, seeking approval, approval, service
なにもない　なにもない　私なにもない　ねえ
Nothing, nothing, I have nothing, hey
はしたない　はしたない　私はしたない　ねえ
Indecent, indecent, I'm indecent, hey
分からない　分からない　分かる　分からない
I don't know, I don't know, I know, I don't know
はーい　自撮りは全部加工して
Yes, processing all my selfies
ダダダダ　ダーリンダーリン　FUNNY
Da-da-da-da, darling, darling, FUNNY
はい絶えない愛情論で冷めたり
Yes, cooling off with endless theories of love
ダダダダ　ダーリン無理ダーリン　DIRTY & DIRTY
Da-da-da-da, darling, no way darling, DIRTY & DIRTY
会いたい衝動　止めてよ　ダダダダ
Stop the urge to meet you, da-da-da-da
踊れ　叫べ　踊れ　ルラッパパ
Dance, scream, dance, lu-la-pa-pa
踊れ　唄え　踊れ　ルラッパパ
Dance, sing, dance, lu-la-pa-pa
ドキドキの　シドケドケの
Heart-pounding, untidy
はい素顔は全部無くして
Yes, getting rid of my real face entirely
ダダダダ　ダーリンダーリン　FUNNY
Da-da-da-da, darling, darling, FUNNY
どうしようもない感情論に笑ったり
Laughing at helpless emotional theories
ダダダダ　ダーリン脳裏　DIRTY & DIRTY
Da-da-da-da, darling, in my mind, DIRTY & DIRTY
会いたい衝動　埋めてよ　ダダダダ
Bury the urge to meet you, da-da-da-da
ナナナナナナナナナナ
Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na
無い無い反応　返答を期待したり
No, no response; expecting an answer
ナナナナナナナナナナ
Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na
無い無い妄想　感傷でダーリン
No, no delusions; darling with sentiment
無い無い情緒　感傷でダダダダ　ねえダーリン
No, no emotions; da-da-da-da with sentiment, hey darling
（チュッ）
(Kiss sound)
ふー...
Phew...
ああ、お粥先輩！
Ah, Okayu-senpai!
お粥先輩！
Okayu-senpai!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
わー、ありがとう！二人とも来てくれてありがとう！
Wow, thank you! Thank you both for coming!
いやー、お誘いありがとうございます！
No, thank you for inviting us!
めっちゃ嬉しいよ。
I'm so happy.
気になってたんだけど、どうしてこの三人で歌おうって思ってくださったんですか？
I was curious, why did you think of having us three sing together?
そう。僕はね、かなたんとマリンちゃんの歌声がめっちゃ好きで。
Right. Well, I really love Kanatan's and Marine-chan's singing voices.
えー！？
Ehh!?
で、二人も僕の歌好きって言ってくれてるの知ってたから...
And I knew you two also said you liked my singing...
大好き！
I love it!
めっちゃ好き！
Really love it!
それに肖ってね、三人で歌わせてもらっちゃおうかなと思って。
So I thought I'd take advantage of that and have us three sing together.
いやー嬉しいですね！
Wow, that's great!
めっちゃ嬉しい！
So happy!
あとは、マリンちゃんとかなたんっててぇてぇから、てぇてぇの間になんか「かなまり」にこう割って入っちゃおうかなって。
Also, because Marine-chan and Kanatan are wholesome, I thought I'd try to cut in between 'KanaMari'.
いや、そんな... 割って入るほどの仲じゃない！
No, we're not... not close enough for you to 'cut in'!
ここ、そんなに繋がってないよね。
We're not that connected here.
そんなに尊い感じのあれじゃないんですよ。
It's not that precious of a thing.
入らなくても割れてます、大丈夫。
It's already split without you entering, it's fine.
そっか、なんか二人の間に入って、なんかそのてぇてぇの間に入ると、死神にちょっと刈られちゃうかなと思った。
I see. I thought if I got in between that wholesomeness, I might get reaped by the Grim Reaper.
いやいやいや...
No, no, no...
むしろね、かなおか（かなた＆おかゆ）の間に入るマリンになってますもんね。
Rather, it's Marine getting between KanaOka.
いやちょっと違うから。あのね、今時はね、もうかなおかの時代は終わっていて...
No, that's a bit different. You see, nowadays, the era of KanaOka is over...
なんで終わらせるの！？
Why are you ending it!?
今からマリオカ（マリン＆おかゆ）の時代よ！
From now on, it's the era of MariOka!
マリオカート！？
Mario Kart!?
マリオカ！
MariOka!
取って付けたような！何言ってんだよ！
That sounds so forced! What are you saying!?
いやおかゆんはね、マリーンのこと好きなのよ、ねー！
No, Okayun loves Marine, right!?
あはははは！
Aha-ha-ha-ha!
何でタイミング良くお水飲んでんだよ！
Why are you drinking water at this timing!?
マリンエネルギー出るわー。
Marine energy is coming out!
まあまあまあ、今日はね、僕の誕生日に免じて三人で仲良くしようよ。
Now, now, today, for the sake of my birthday, let's all three get along.
おかゆ先輩がそう言うなら...
If Okayu-senpai says so...
そうだよ、ほら、手を繋いで。ハイチーズ！
That's right. Here, hold hands. Say cheese!
楽しい！
So fun!
おかゆ先輩、強引だわー！
Okayu-senpai, you're so pushy!
まだ言わないで　呪文めいたその言葉
Don't say it yet, those words that sound like a spell
愛なんて　羽のように軽い
Love is as light as a feather
囁いて　パパより優しい手つきで
Whisper to me with hands gentler than father's
奪う覚悟があるのならば
If you are prepared to take me away
百万本の薔薇のベッドに
In a bed of a million roses
埋もれ見る夢よりも
More than the dreams I see buried within
香ぐわしく私は生きてるの
I live more fragrantly
どうすれば醜いものが
How can I avoid the ugly things
蔓延ったこの世界
Infesting this world?
汚れずに羽ばたいて行けるのか
Can I flap my wings without being defiled?
ひとり繭の中
Alone inside a cocoon
学びつづけても
Even if I continue to learn
水晶の星空は遠すぎるの
The crystal starry sky is much too far
まだ触れないでその震える指先は
Don't touch me yet; those trembling fingertips
花盗人の甘いためらい
Are the sweet hesitation of a flower-thief
触れてもいいこの深い胸の奥にまで
You may touch me, if you have the confidence
届く自信があるのならば
To reach deep into the depths of my heart
白馬の王子様なんて
It's not that I believe
信じてるわけじゃない
In a Prince Charming on a white horse
君は冷えたガラスケースに
You are the purity adorned
飾られた純潔は
In a cold glass case
滅びゆく天使たちの心臓
The heart of perishing angels
また明日目覚めるたびに
Every time I wake up tomorrow
百年の刻を知る
I feel the passing of a hundred years
眠れない魂の茨姫
A sleepless soul, a Briar Rose
くいこむ冠に
In the crown biting deep
ひとしずくの血に
In a single drop of blood
ああ現実が真実と思い知るの
Ah, I realize that reality is truth
まだ行かないで月明かりの結界で
Don't go yet; in this moonlight barrier
過ちに気づいてしまいそう
I feel I might notice my mistakes
安らかなぬくもり抱かれ壊れたい
I want to be broken, held in peaceful warmth
私は罪の子なのでしょうか
Am I a child of sin?
そっとこぼれてくる涙の
I don't even know the meaning
意味さえわからない
Of the tears gently spilling out
もう言わないで呪文めいたその言葉
Don't say those spell-like words anymore
愛なんて鎖のように重い
Love is as heavy as chains
囁いてパパより優しいテノールで
Whisper in a tenor voice gentler than my father's
どんな覚悟もできるならば
If you are prepared for anything
さあ誓ってよその震える唇で
Now, vow with those trembling lips
蜜を摘む狩人のときめき
The excitement of a hunter gathering nectar
さらっていいこの深い胸の奥底
You may take me away, if you have the courage
射抜く勇気があるのならば
To shoot through the depths of my heart
貴方捕らえたら決して
Once I've captured you, I'll make sure
逃がさないようにして
You never escape
あー！アキちゃん！
Ah! Aki-chan!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
おかゆー！
Okayuuu!
もうちょっと興奮してさ...
I'm so excited...
まあ、ちょっとすごい息荒くなってるんだけど、ごめんね。
Well, my breathing is getting really heavy, sorry.
えー、アキちゃんアキちゃん、改めて。
Hey, Aki-chan, Aki-chan, once again.
今日は僕の誕生日なんだよ。
Today is my birthday.
知ってるよ！お祝いに来たんだもん！
I know! That's why I came to celebrate!
アキちゃん！
Aki-chan!
いや、なんかさ、僕とアキちゃんは...
Well, you see, Aki-chan and I...
こうなんだろうな、配信とかで一緒に絡んでるところを...
...how should I put it, we haven't shown ourselves interacting much on streams...
あんまり見せたことがないから、みんなもしかしたら知らないかもしれないけど...
...so everyone might not know, but...
アキちゃんは僕のことが大好きなんだよ。
Aki-chan loves me very much.
そう、実はね、アキロゼ...
Yes, actually, Aki Rose...
こう見えてめちゃくちゃおにぎりゃーなんだよね。
...might look like this, but is a huge Onigirya.
僕もアキちゃんの声とかも超大好きだから...
I also really love Aki-chan's voice and everything...
えー！
Eeeh!
もう僕もロゼ隊みたいなとこあるから。
I'm almost like a Rose-tai member myself.
え、そんな、両想いじゃん、てなってたんだよ。
I was like, "Wait, it's mutual love!"
嬉しすぎるー！
I'm so happy!
そうで、それでね、今日一緒に歌えたらなと思ってね、声をかけたら、
Right, and so, I thought it would be great if we could sing together today, and when I asked her,
こう『いいよ』って言ってくれたのアキちゃん。
Aki-chan said "Okay."
そうだよー！もうどれだけね、
That's right! No matter how,
もう忙しいと思っても、おかゆんのためならえんやこらー！
no matter how busy I might be, for Okayun's sake, it's no problem!
アキちゃんもね、すごい忙しい中今日時間作ってくれてさ、もう本当に嬉しいんだよ。
Aki-chan also made time for me today despite being so busy, I'm really happy.
これで終わりだねって
Saying "this is the end,"
最後の言葉になるけど
though these are my last words,
ありがとね
thank you.
わあー！
Waaa!
あくあ、来てくれてありがとう！
Aqua, thank you for coming!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとう、あくあ。
Thank you, Aqua.
いや、おかゆ、まさかこの誕生日に呼んでくれるなんて。
Wow, Okayu, I didn't expect you'd invite me on your birthday.
まあ、あくあもね、よくあくあのライブに僕のこと呼んでくれるからさ。
Well, you often invite me to your live shows too, Aqua.
そうだね。
That's true.
今日はさ、僕はあくあのこと呼びたいなと思って呼ばせてもらったんだよね。
So today, I wanted to invite you, and that's why you're here.
そんなに私と一緒に歌いたかったのおかゆ？
Did you want to sing with me that much, Okayu?
え？ 私のこと好き？ いい？
Eh? Do you like me? Hehe?
なに…ちょっと待って、それ私が言うやつだから。
What... wait, that's supposed to be my line.
私のこと好き？ いい？
Do you like me? Hehe?
そんなんじゃないよ、そんなんじゃないから。
It's not like that, it's really not.
もっと可愛いよ、もっと可愛いよ。
It's much cuter than that, much cuter.
そっか。
I see.
まあでも今日はね、あくあと、まああくあに最初に教えてもらった
But really, today, with Aqua, singing the song she first taught me,
夜撫でるメノウ、今日は二人で歌えてすごい嬉しかったよ。
"Yoru Naderu Menou" together, I was really happy.
いや本当ね、この曲やっぱね、私たちの愛のラブソング。
Yeah, really, this song is after all our love song of love.
愛のラブソング？
Love song of love?
そうだよ。
That's right.
え？ 何か流しそうめんしたくなった曲じゃなかった？
Eh? Wasn't it a song that made you want to do Nagashi-somen?
流しそうめんはしたくなるね、この曲なんだか。
This song does kind of make me want to do Nagashi-somen.
したい、したいのなんか。
I want to do it, somehow.
ね。
Right.
いやでもさ、なんか沁み沁みしちゃったよ、一緒に歌ってて。
But man, I got a bit emotional singing it with you.
ね。
Yeah.
すごいおかゆと歌えてよかったよ、本当にありがとう。
I'm so glad I could sing with you, Okayu. Thank you so much.
じゃさ、僕があくあのライブに出させてもらってるとき、
Well then, when I appear as a guest in your live shows,
いつもね、僕があくあを置いてきぼりで帰るっていうのがお約束になってるけど。
it's always a given that I leave you behind and go home.
お約束？
A given?
うん。
Yeah.
今日は、あくあが帰ってもいい日にするよ。
But today, I'll make it a day where you can be the one to go home.
うん？ え？
Huh? Eh?
帰らないよ、私。
I'm not going home.
え？
Eh?
え、今日はもうここの現場に居続ける気で来た。
Eh, I came here today intending to stay at this venue.
え？
Eh?
そしたらおかゆとずっと一緒にいられるわけでしょ？
Then I can stay with you forever, right?
おかゆいつも帰っちゃうから。
Since you always go home, Okayu.
じゃ、しょうがない。今日も僕が帰りますか。
Well then, it can't be helped. Shall I go home today too?
ちょっと！ おかゆ！
Wait! Okayu!
またね！ バイバイ！
See ya! Bye-bye!
やめて！ ここにいてよ！
Don't! Stay here!
おかゆ！ やめてやめてやめて！ 私ずっとここいるからね！
Okayu! Stop, stop, stop! I'm staying here forever!
いるからね！ いるからね、ここ！ いや、やだ！ やだ！
I'm staying! I'm staying right here! No, I don't want to! No!
「あたし計算はイマイチ 引き算ばっかり」
"I'm not so good at math, it's nothing but subtractions"
「自然数xを求めよとか そういうのわかんない」
"Solve for natural number x? I don't get that stuff"
「あたし国語もイマイチ 鉛筆ころがし」
"I'm not so good at Japanese either, just rolling my pencil"
「筆者の心境として適切なものを選びなさい」
"Choose the option that best describes the author's feelings"
「っつか宿題終わんnight」
"I mean, this homework's never gonna end-night"
ハイ誰も気づかない
Hi, no one will notice.
ちょっとぐらいショック食らわせて
Let's give them a bit of a shock.
それじゃダメだって　誰かに叱ってほしい
I want someone to scold me, saying "that's no good".
なぐさめるなら後にして
If you're going to comfort me, do it later.
さよなら涙　はじめまして涙
Goodbye tears, nice to meet you tears.
振り出しまで戻れない
I can't go back to the start.
よくいる女ね　愛おしいね　なにか？
I'm just an ordinary woman, isn't that lovely? What of it?
バカにしないで　はやくして
Don't make a fool of me, hurry up.
救われたいよね　なんか文句あるのかよ
We want to be saved, right? Do you have a problem with that?
遊びじゃねえんだよ　あとにして
This isn't a game, do it later.
やさしさなんか　どこでもいい
Kindness or whatever, it doesn't matter.
流されるなら　いまにして
If you're going to be swept away, do it now.
おい！おかゆ！おめでとう！
Hey! Okayu! Happy birthday!
えー！スバルちゃん！お祝いに来てくれたの？
Eh! Subaru-chan! You came to celebrate?
お祝いに来てくれたってなんだよ、こんだけ踊っといて！
What do you mean "came to celebrate", after dancing this much!
踊って歌っといて、お祝いに来たよ！おめでとう！
I danced and sang, so yes, I came to celebrate! Congrats!
ありがとう。そう、スバルちゃんがね、僕の好きな歌を覚えて、
Thank you. That's right, Subaru-chan learned my favorite song,
踊りまで覚えてきてくれたんだよ！
and even learned the dance for it!
そうなんです。もう、なかなかの大変さでした。
That's right. Man, it was quite a struggle.
普段歌わないから、こういう曲。
Since I don't usually sing songs like this.
そうだよね。なんか僕、スバルちゃんの
Right? I just thought I'd like to hear
カッコいい歌声聞いてみたいなと思って。
Subaru-chan's cool singing voice.
そう、一緒にね、歌いたかったんだよ！
Yeah, I wanted to sing together!
だって、もう、なんだったら一回、その、
I mean, if anything, once...
もうマジで、正解わかんなすぎて...
honestly, I had no idea what the "correct" way was...
ど深夜に歌撮って、「こんな感じ、歌う感じでいいの？」って
I recorded my singing in the dead of night and sent it,
送って、監修してもらったからね。
asking "Is this how I should sing it?", to get your supervision.
いや、でもスバルちゃんは、なんかその、不安がってるわりに、
Well, even though Subaru-chan was worried,
ちゃんと歌ってるから、逆にコメントに困るよね。
she sang it perfectly, so it's actually hard to find anything to comment on.
だってお前、ちゃんと歌わないといけないだろ！
Well, of course I have to sing it right!
大事な僕の誕生日だもんね！
It's my important birthday after all!
自分、自分で言うなよ。
Don't say it yourself.
自分、自分で言うなよ、お前。言わせてくれよ、
Don't say it yourself, you. Let me say it
そこはちゃんと。
properly, at least.
いいよ、言ってもらって。いやいや、もう大丈夫です、ありがとうございます。
Fine, you can say it. No, no, it's fine, thank you.
なんでよ！えー、僕の誕生日にも、スバルちゃんは照れてくれないの？
Why not! Eh, you won't get bashful for me even on my birthday, Subaru-chan?
いや、照れないだろ。別に。いや、いつも照れてるだろ、むしろ！
No, I'm not gonna get bashful. Not really. Actually, I'm always bashful!
あ、そうなの。
Oh, is that so?
心当たりないんかい！
You don't even realize it?!
こんだけ愛情かけてたのに、何にも感じてくれてないじゃん！
I've given you so much love, yet you haven't felt a thing!
いや、もっとスバルちゃんが照れたら、
No, I thought if Subaru-chan got more bashful,
「スバルもー！」みたいな感じになるのかと思ってたからさ。
it'd be like, "Oh, Subaru, you!"
いや、ならねえわ、ごめん。ならねえのか。
No, that's not happening, sorry. Oh, it's not?
まあ、でもね、スバルちゃん、今日は、あの、僕の誕生日に、
Well, anyway, Subaru-chan, thank you for coming to celebrate
お祝いに来てくれてありがとう！チュッ！
my birthday today! *Chu*!
うわぁ！おい失礼だぞ！
Waaaa! Hey, that's rude!
嬉しいんだけど、なんか胸に来た今。
I'm happy, but it hit me right in the chest just now.
切なさと、嬉しさが同時に来た、今。
A mix of sadness and joy hit me at the same time.
じゃあ、最後にね、ちょっとみんなにも、最大級のね、
Well then, finally, show everyone your best
可愛いポーズか、なんかいい感じのおかゆのポーズしてよ！
cute pose or some nice Okayu-style pose!
わかった。行くよ！じゃあ...
Understood. Here I go! Then...
ダブルおかゆ！
Double Okayu!
あざーす。おめでとう。じゃーねー！
Thanks. Congrats. See ya!
おい！おい！これじゃ、食い逃げじゃなくて、
Hey! Hey! This isn't just "eat and run",
メス逃げじゃねえか！
it's "mess around and run"!
それ言いたいだけやん。
You just wanted to say that.
G... R...
Double E, N, Leaves!
It's so easy! Happy go lucky!
We are the world! We are the...
ヒューヒューヒューヒュー！
Hyu Hyu Hyu Hyu!
やった！やった！やった！やった！
Yatta! Yatta! Yatta! Yatta!
大学合格！
Passed the college exam!
やった！やった！やった！やった！
Yatta! Yatta! Yatta! Yatta!
葉っぱ一枚あればいい
All I need is a single leaf.
生きているからラッキーだ
I'm lucky just to be alive.
やった！やった！やった！やった！
Yatta! Yatta! Yatta! Yatta!
日本代表！当選確実！
Representing Japan! Guaranteed victory!
やんなるくらい健康だ
I'm so healthy it's almost annoying.
Everybody say!
やったー！
YATTA!
日本キューキュー
Japan's in a pinch
でも明日はワンダホー
But tomorrow will be wonderful
いじわるされても
Even if someone is mean to me
布団入ればグーグーグー
Once I'm in bed, I'm fast asleep
パスパスパス
Pass, pass, pass
おはよー！
Good morning!
やった やった 昼寝もついでに やった やった
Yatta, yatta, while I'm at it, I took a nap, yatta, yatta
寝起きで最高 どんな良いことあるだろう
Waking up is the best, I wonder what good things will happen
生きていたからラッキーだ
I'm lucky because I'm alive
やった やった 君が変われば やった やった
Yatta, yatta, if you change, yatta, yatta
世界も変わる まるごしだから最強だ
The world will change too, I'm at my strongest when I've got nothing
まっすぐ立ったら 気持ちいいー！
Standing up straight feels so good!
オス オス オス オス
Ossu, ossu, ossu, ossu
お水飲んだらうめー！
Drinking water tastes so good!
やったー！
Yatta!
日に当たったらあったけー！
Basking in the sun feels so warm!
やったー！
Yatta!
腹から笑ったらおもしれー！
Laughing from the gut is so funny!
やったやったー！
Yatta, yatta!
犬飼ってみたらかわいー！
Getting a dog is so cute!
やったー！
Yatta!
It's so easy
Happy go lucky
We are the world
We are the... ヒューヒュー
We are the... Hwee hwee!
オス オス オス オス
Ossu, ossu, ossu, ossu
すれ違いざま ほほえみくれた
As we passed each other, you gave me a smile
二度と会えなくたっていい 君がいたからラッキーだ
It's okay if we never meet again, I'm lucky just because you were there
平成不況 政治不信
The Heisei recession, distrust in politics
リセットさえすりゃ最高だ
If we just reset it all, it'll be the best
みんな居るから楽しいー！
It's fun because everyone is here!
やった やった 大学教授 やった やった
Yatta, yatta, university professor, yatta, yatta
ムービースター 葉っぱ一枚あればいい
Movie star, as long as I have a single leaf
みんな一緒だ HAPPYだ
Everyone is together, we're happy
やった やった 息を吸える やった やった
Yatta, yatta, I can breathe, yatta, yatta
息を吐ける やんなるくらい健康だ
I can breathe out, I'm so healthy it's almost annoying
Everybody say!
やったー！
Yatta!
バイキュ〜！
By-kyu!
はい、ということで！
Alright, so!
ゲーマーズお久しぶりでございます！
It's been a while, Gamers!
前回会ったのは多分、白上の誕生日ですかね？
The last time we met was probably for Fubuki's birthday?
記念日にしか会えないゲーマーズ。
Gamers who only meet on anniversaries.
いやいや、でもありがとうございます今日は！
Anyway, thank you so much for today!
おめでとうー！おかゆおめでとうー！
Congratulations! Happy birthday, Okayu!
頭に葉っぱをつけてね！
With leaves on our heads!
そう、葉っぱつけて踊りましたけども。
Yeah, we danced with leaves on.
やっぱゲーマーズと言えば、ちょっとね、全力でおふざけをするチームじゃないですか、我々は。
When you think of Gamers, we're a team that fools around with all our might, aren't we?
集まらないけどね！
Even though we don't gather much!
自由なのはいいことですよ。
Being free is a good thing.
自由度は高いね、我々ね。
We do have a high degree of freedom.
で、選ばれたのがこちらの葉っぱ隊の...
And what we chose was this Leaf Squad...
僕、前からゲーマーズで葉っぱ隊の『YATTA!』を踊って歌いたかったんだよ。
I've wanted to sing and dance to the Leaf Squad's 'YATTA!' with Gamers for a long time.
だから、自分の誕生日にこの夢が叶ってすごく嬉しいんだよ！
So I'm really happy that this dream came true on my birthday!
頭に葉っぱつけてね！
With leaves on our heads!
なんかさ、『YATTA!』の歌詞の中でさ、みんな何が好き？なんかワードみたいなの。
By the way, what do you guys like in the lyrics of 'YATTA!'? Like a specific word or phrase.
あー、フブキはね、『WE ARE THE... ヒューヒュー！』めっちゃ好き。
Ah, for me, I really like 'WE ARE THE... Hwee hwee!'.
あそこね、めっちゃ楽しかった。
That part was really fun.
うちは『息が吸える、息が吐ける』。当たり前だけど、当たり前じゃない、みたいな。
For me, it's 'I can breathe in, I can breathe out.' It's something we take for granted, but it's not actually.
やっぱ『日本キューキュー』かな！『でも！』みたいな。あそこ好き。
I guess 'Japan's in a pinch'! And then the 'But!' part. I like that.
僕は、やっぱ『お水飲んだらうめー！』。当たり前だけど最高じゃん、お水って。
For me, it's definitely 'Drinking water tastes so good!'. It's simple, but water is the best, isn't it?
『YATTA!』『YATTA!』ってね。めちゃめちゃ楽しかった、本当に！
Saying 'YATTA!', 'YATTA!'. It was so much fun, really!
この4人で歌えてよかったね。
I'm glad we could sing together, us four.
わー！やったー！
Yay! We did it!
ゲームスもね、コラボもしよう！ゲームもコラボもしよう！
Gamers too, let's collab! Let's do a gaming collab too!
ゲーマーズ最高だからねー！
Gamers are the best!
え、じゃあさ、この4人で歌った感想さ、なんか、ちょっと簡単に…
So, how about a quick word on how it felt to sing as a group of four...
や、でも、やっぱりこれはめちゃくちゃ聞いてると元気が出るから、
Well, listening to this song really gives you energy,
やっぱね、こう、今聞いてくれてるみんなも、リスナー諸君もね、疲れたらまたこのゲーマーズのやつを聴きに来てほしいなって思うよ。
so I hope everyone listening, all you listeners, come back to hear the Gamers version whenever you're tired.
めっちゃいいコメントいただきました！
What a great comment!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
でもさ、なんかやっぱさ、おかゆってさ、歌聴いてて思ったけど、歌上手いよね！
But you know, listening to her sing, I really thought... Okayu, you're a great singer!
たしかに！あ、たしかに思う！上手い！
True! I totally agree! You're good!
あれ？なんか葉っぱが…あれ？大きくなってない？
Wait? The leaves... aren't they getting bigger?
おかゆ可愛い！可愛い！
Okayu, you're cute! So cute!
上手い！歌上手いよ！上手い！
You're good! Such a good singer! You're great!
わ！やばいやばいやばい！
Whoa! Oh no, no, no!
デカいよ！デカくなっちゃった！
It's huge! It got so big!
キモい、ちょっとキモい。
It's gross, a bit gross.
おかゆ大好き！大好きだよ！
We love you, Okayu! We really do!
やばい！おかゆ！デカいデカい！
Crazy! Okayu! It's huge, huge!
デカいデカい！キモいよデカい！
It's so big! It's gross how big it is!
Daphne
Ficus
Iris
Maackia
Lythrum
Myrica
Salvia
Phlox
flos
拝啓 僕の願いよ 未来よ 絶え間のない後悔よ
Dearly, my wishes, the future, and the unending regrets
体感八度五分の夢は やがて散ってしまった
The dream at 8.5 degrees of perceived temperature has eventually scattered
再啓 君の想いは 憂いは 巡る感情論は
Re-reply, your thoughts, the sorrow, and the cyclical emotional arguments
半径八十五分の世界に 囚われたまま
Remain imprisoned in a world with a radius of 85 minutes
本音を挿し 罅割れた今日を 溢れた一切に
Inserting my true feelings into this cracked today, into all that overflowed
薪を焚べて 風に乗せて 錆びた空を彩る
Burning the firewood, letting it ride the wind, coloring the rusted sky
燻んだ日々を丁寧に 飾った花はすぐに枯れてく
The flowers that carefully adorned these dull days quickly wither away
愚鈍な僕は夢から醒めて 縋った意味も無いな無いな
Dull as I am, I wake from the dream; there's no meaning in what I clung to
君が僕にくれた声も色も 揺るぎない愛情も
The voice and colors you gave me, and that unwavering affection
二人きりの空に光った星も とっくに散ってしまった
Even the star that shone in our private sky has long since scattered
難儀の末のモノクロの疲弊に 季節は色褪せて
In the monochrome exhaustion at the end of hardships, the seasons fade
熱を帯びて 鈍く膿んで 擦れた街に零れる
Growing feverish, dullly festering, spilling out into the worn-down town
荒んだ日々を丁寧に 辿った先に花が咲くはず
Flowers should bloom at the end of carefully tracing these desolate days
利口な君は夢を見たまま 悟った振りで水を注いだ
Clever as you are, still dreaming, you poured water while pretending to understand
木漏れ日の中に柔らかく咲いた花は
The flowers that bloomed softly in the dappled sunlight
雲の上で違う星で夢の先で揺れてる
Are swaying above the clouds, on a different star, beyond the dream
燻んだ日々を丁寧に 飾った花はすぐに枯れてく
The flowers that carefully adorned these dull days quickly wither away
愚鈍な僕は...
Dull as I am...
愚鈍な僕は夢から覚めて
Stupid me, waking up from a dream
縋った意味も無い無いないないな
The meaning I clung to is gone, gone, gone
不毛な日々を丁寧に丁寧に
Taking care, taking care of these fruitless days
綴った紙に花を描いた
I drew flowers on the paper I wrote on
不遇な僕ら夢に敗れて
Unfortunate us, defeated by our dreams
誓ったはずも無かった事にした
We pretended our oaths never existed
Daphne
Ficus
Iris
Maackia
Lythrum
Myrica
Sabia
Thymus
Ribes
Abelia
Sedum
Felicia
Ochna
Lychnis
flos
No title
作詞・作曲：れをる
Lyrics & Composition: Reol
ずっと夢見てた僕になれたかな とうに帰れないとこまで来たみたい
Did I become the person I always dreamed of?
Seems I've come too far to ever go back
自分の足で二段飛ばして もっと先へ駆けていけるはずだから run away
Skipping two steps at a time with my own feet,
I should be able to run even further, so run away
深くなる傷を縫い付け 繋ぐパッチワークに回り出す
Sewing up the deepening wounds,
the patchwork starts to spin around
慣れた痛み 焦る呼吸とビート 気付かない振りしてまた一人
The familiar pain, the hurried breath and the beat,
pretending not to notice, alone again
何が正当？ないな永劫 誰が間違い？対価払うの
What's right? Nothing, forever.
Who's wrong? Paying the price
あんたが嫌いな あいつはきっと ただそれだけで不正解なんだ
The person you hate is surely wrong
just because of that
0点だって提言したって 全然納得できない理由も
Even if I declare it's zero points,
even for the reasons I can't accept at all
最前線はいつだってここだった 最善策は最初からなかった
The front line was always right here.
There was no best plan from the start
緩やかに崩れ壊れてく
Slowly crumbling and breaking down
ゆるりゆるり首を締めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
Slowly, slowly, as if strangling me,
the me of yesterday is being killed
緩やかに離れ離れ ああ
Slowly drifting apart, ah
ぐらりんり君に聞こえるのは 僕が知らない声になってく
Dizzily, what you hear is becoming a voice I don't know
幼い頃から気付いたら傍にいた まるで空気のようだ
Ever since I was little, you were by my side
before I knew it. Just like the air
僕は君ときゅっと手を繋いで
I tightly held your hand
楽しいことも涙も僕は君に話して聞かせた
I told you about the fun things and the tears
僕を笑う人 貶す声が聞こえぬように君は歌った
You sang so that I couldn't hear the people
laughing at me or the voices belittling me
この声を君が受信 また夜毎投影されていく愛
You receive this voice, and love is projected
every night
使い捨てだって いつか腐っても止まらないハイファイ 在処外
Even if it's disposable, even if it rots someday,
the non-stop hi-fi is where it is
一周巡る間の たった一瞬だけでも
Even for just a single moment in a full rotation
交わる鼓動、音、繋ぐ色 次は僕が君に歌うから
Heartbeats, sounds, colors that connect...
Next, I'll sing for you
緩やかに崩れ壊れてく
Slowly crumbling and breaking down
ゆるりゆるり首を締めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
Slowly, slowly, as if strangling me,
the me of yesterday is being killed
緩やかに離れ離れ ああ
Slowly drifting apart, ah
ぐらりんり君に聞こえるのは 僕が知らない声になってく
Dizzily, what you hear is becoming a voice I don't know
緩やかに崩れ壊れてく
Slowly crumbling and breaking down
ゆるりゆるり首を締めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
Slowly, slowly, as if strangling me,
the me of yesterday is being killed
緩やかに離れ離れ ああ
Slowly drifting apart, ah
ぐらりんり君に聞こえるのは 僕が知らない声になってく
Dizzily, what you hear is becoming a voice I don't know
いつか君に届くかな いやそんな日はきっと来ないだろうな
Will it reach you someday?
No, such a day surely won't come
声も身体も持たぬ君に 救われた何億人の一人
One of the hundreds of millions saved by you,
who has neither voice nor body
赤青今合わせ彩った 音で世界が溢れた
Mixing red and blue now,
the world was filled with the sounds we colored
巡り巡り出会ったこの音を聴くすべてが
Everything that hears this sound we encountered
as it came around again...
緩やかに崩れ壊れてく
Slowly crumbling and breaking down
ゆるりゆるり首を締めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
Slowly, slowly, as if strangling me,
the me of yesterday is being killed
緩やかに離れ離れ ああ
Slowly drifting apart, ah
ぐらりんり君に聞こえるのは 僕が知らない声になってく
Dizzily, what you hear is becoming a voice I don't know
緩やかに崩れ壊れてく
Slowly crumbling and breaking down
ゆるりゆるり首を締めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
Slowly, slowly, as if strangling me,
the me of yesterday is being killed
緩やかに離れ離れ ああ
Slowly drifting apart, ah
ぐらりんり君に聞こえるのは 僕が知らない声になってく
Dizzily, what you hear is becoming a voice I don't know
ああ、おかゆ改めておめでとう！
Ah, Okayu, once again, congratulations!
ありがとう、ころさん。
Thank you, Koro-san.
なんかこの曲一緒に歌いたいって言ってもらえて、すごいね、嬉しかったわ。
I was really happy when you said you wanted to sing this song together.
そう、なんか、この歌の歌詞がね、
Yeah, like, the lyrics of this song...
歌詞の中に、
contain things in them...
こう、すごく僕がころさんに対して思ってるなーっていうこととか、
that I feel really strongly for Koro-san...
ころさんが僕に対してこんなふうに思ってくれてたら嬉しいなーっていうことが、
and things I'd be happy if Koro-san felt for me too,
なんかたくさん詰まってるなーと思ったから、
so I thought there's a lot packed in there...
これをね、自分の誕生日に一緒に歌いたかったんだ。
that's why I wanted to sing this with you on my birthday.
嬉しい。
I'm happy.
あのね、唐突だけどね、今日お手紙書いてきたの。
You know, it's sudden, but I wrote a letter today.
えー？！
Eh?!
ちょっと読ませていただきます。
I'd like to read it.
うん。
Yeah.
おかゆへ。おかゆお誕生日おめでとう。
To Okayu. Okayu, happy birthday.
おかゆはいつもころねをたくさん褒めてくれるけど、今日はころねがおかゆを褒めたいと思います。
Okayu always praises Koone a lot, but today Koone wants to praise Okayu.
おかゆは本当に歌が上手いです。
Okayu is really good at singing.
艶があって、色気があって、ずっと聞いていたい歌声。
Your voice is glossy and sexy, a singing voice I want to listen to forever.
おかゆは本当に優しいです。
Okayu is really kind.
ころねが悲しい時、自分のことのように悲しんでくれるし、
When Koone is sad, you feel sad as if it were your own,
ころねが傷ついた時、ギュッとして慰めてくれます。
and when Koone is hurt, you hug me and comfort me.
おかゆは本当に面白いです。
Okayu is really funny.
おかゆが喋ったことでたくさん腹筋が割れたよ。
I've laughed so hard at what you say that my abs hurt.
いつでもどこでもころねを支えてくれるおかゆ、
Okayu, who supports Koone anytime, anywhere,
ころねもずっとずっとそんなおかゆを支えていきます。
Koone will also support Okayu forever and ever.
生まれてきてくれてありがとう。ころねより。
Thank you for being born. From Koone.
ころさーん！
Koro-saaan!
おかゆ、おめでとう！おめでとう！
Okayu, congratulations! Congratulations!
めっちゃ嬉しい。え、そのお手紙さ、記念に持って帰ってもいい？
I'm so happy. Um, can I take that letter home as a memento?
いや、あの、後でちょっと清書...あ、違う、ちゃんと書くから、これは...
No, well, later I'll... I'll write it properly, this is...
いいよいいよ、それで！
It's fine, it's fine! Just that!
違うの、違うの！
No, it's different!
全然いいよ！
It's totally fine!
待って待って、違うの！
Wait, wait, it's different!
え？
Eh?
これさ、チラシの裏じゃねーかよおおおお！
Wait, isn't this the back of a flyer?!
どっか行きやがった！
She went away!
まあなんか、しょうがない、一人になったからね、この後のことでも話そうかな。
Well, I guess it can't be helped since I'm alone now. I'll talk about what's next.
この後は、僕の二個目の新しいオリジナル曲のお披露目になるから、
Next up is the debut of my second new original song,
聞いてってよね。
so please listen.
そこにいるころさんも、
To Koro-san over there,
みんなも！
and everyone else too!
では、聞いてください。
Well then, please listen.
新しい僕のオリジナル曲、
My new original song,
デタバレネコ。
Detabareneko.
デタバレネコ
作詞：猫又おかゆ・Neko Hacker
作曲・編曲：Neko Hacker
Detabareneko
Lyrics: Okayu Nekomata, Neko Hacker
Composition & Arrangement: Neko Hacker
酸いも甘いも全部 噛み合わせ
Biting into the bitters and the sweets
地味な日常に目眩う
Dizzy in the plain daily life
気付けばなにも選べなくなって
Before I knew it, I couldn't choose anything
僕ら大人になったんだ
And we became adults
被害者ヅラは違ったか
Was playing the victim wrong?
取り戻そうよ 奪還だ！
Let's take it back, it's a recovery!
右見て 左見て
Look right, look left,
三回回ってにゃんにゃんにゃん
spin three times, nyan nyan nyan
右見て 左見て
Look right, look left,
三回回ってにゃんにゃんにゃん
spin three times, nyan nyan nyan
全部自分で選んできた
I chose it all myself
全部自分で決めたんだ
I decided it all myself
後付けだけのねつ造だ
It's just a fabrication after the fact
ああ 僕は世界の誰からも愛される
Ah, I could never become
存在には...なれなかったけど
a being loved by everyone in the world, but...
何者にもなれなかったけど
Even though I couldn't become anybody,
君のとなりで笑っていたかったな
I wanted to be laughing by your side
デタラメな気持ちを歌に乗せるよ
I'll put my nonsensical feelings into a song
ネタバレはやめてよね
No spoilers, please
いやでもちょっとだけなら？
Or maybe just a little bit?
まあまあ宴もたけなわ
Now, now, the party is in full swing,
さようなら
goodbye
右見て 左見て
Look right, look left,
三回回ってもうやめた
spin three times, I've had enough
右見て 左見て
Look right, look left,
三回回ってもうやめた
spin three times, I've had enough
優しい君が側にいてくれて良かった
I'm glad that the kind you was by my side
厳しい君が側にいてくれて良かった
I'm glad that the strict you was by my side
どうでもいい君も側にいてくれて良かった
I'm glad even the whatever you was by my side
やっぱり嘘
Wait, that was a lie
どうでもいいなんて嘘
'Whatever' was a lie
ああ 僕は世界のどこかで
Ah, to be told that
このままでさ
it's okay for me to exist like this
存在していいんだってことを
somewhere in the world,
感じさせてくれたのは
the one who made me feel that way
君の
was you
そんな言葉だった気がするから
and your words, I think
ああ 僕は世界の誰からも愛される
Ah, I could never become
存在には...なれなかったけど
a being loved by everyone in the world, but...
何者にもなれなかったけど
Even though I couldn't become anybody...
君のとなりに笑っていたかったなぁ
I wanted to be smiling by your side.
デタラメな感情を歌に乗せるよ
I'll put my nonsensical feelings into song.
ネタバレはやめてよね
Stop the spoilers, okay?
いやでもちょっとだけなら
No, but if it's just a little bit...
まあまあ宴もたけなわ
Well, the party is in full swing.
さようなら
Goodbye.
あ、まだ帰っちゃだめ！
Ah, don't leave yet!
えへへ、もう少しだけ僕につきあってね
Ehehe, stay with me for a little longer.
猫又おかゆ誕生日記念グッズ2022、発売します！
Nekomata Okayu Birthday Celebration Goods 2022 are now on sale!
イエーイ！やったー！
Yay! We did it!
グッズの紹介をしていくね
I'm going to introduce the goods.
はじめに紹介するのはこちら、タペストリーだよ
First up is this tapestry.
こちら、僕のママである神岡ちろる先生に描き下ろしてもらったよ
This was drawn by my "mama," Kamioka Chiroru-sensei.
かわいい！
It's cute!
今年はでっかく、いろんなことに挑戦したいという思いを込めて、宇宙スタイルとなっております
This year, it's a space style, reflecting my desire to take on big new challenges.
二つ目、アクリルスタンド＆お茶碗
Second, the acrylic stand and rice bowl.
こちらは大好きななもり先生に描き下ろしをしていただきました
This was drawn by my favorite, Namori-sensei.
このグッズは、アクリルスタンドの僕が持っているお茶碗が、実際にお茶碗としても販売するという
In this set, the rice bowl my acrylic stand version is holding is also sold as a real rice bowl.
ご飯を食べてるときに、近くにアクリルスタンドがあると、
It's a product that makes you feel like you're eating together
一緒にご飯を食べてるような気持ちになれるグッズだよ
when you have the stand nearby while you eat.
ちなみにアクリルスタンドの台座は、座布団となっております。かわいい！
By the way, the base of the acrylic stand is a zabuton cushion. So cute!
三つ目は腹巻
Third is the belly warmer.
このグッズは、僕が描いたイラストが腹巻になったよ。かわいい！
My drawing has been turned into a belly warmer. It's cute!
後ろを向くと尻尾もついてて、猫気分を味わえます
It even has a tail on the back, so you can feel like a cat.
身も心もお腹も、僕が全部守ってあげるからね
I'll protect your body, soul, and stomach.
最後はボイスセットの販売です
Finally, there's a voice set for sale.
ガチ恋向けシチュエーションボイス4種、ショートシチュエーションボイス4種、
It includes 4 'Gachikoi' situation voices, 4 short situation voices,
ふしぎシチュエーションボイス4種、ショートボイス10種となっております
4 'mysterious' situation voices, and 10 short voices.
僕は毎月ASMRをやってるんだけど、また一味違った僕が楽しめること間違いなしです
I do ASMR every month, but you'll definitely enjoy a different side of me here.
あ、そうそう、ASMRで思い出した
Oh, that's right. ASMR reminded me.
今回は誕生日記念フルセット購入特典として、直筆サイン入りポストカードと特典ASMRボイスがついてくるよ
Buying the full birthday set will get you a hand-signed postcard and a bonus ASMR voice.
あ、直筆サイン入りポストカードと聞いて慌てているそこの君
Ah, I see you there, panicking at the mention of a hand-signed postcard.
大丈夫だよ。今回個数制限はないから、フルセット購入してくれる人全員にサインが届くよ
Don't worry. There's no limit on quantity this time, so everyone who buys the full set will get a signature.
えへへ、楽しみにしててね
Ehehe, look forward to it.
大体そんな感じ
That's about it.
今日はたくさんの思い出を、みんなと作れて本当に嬉しかった。ありがとうね
I'm so happy I could make many memories with everyone today. Thank you.
みんなのこと大好きだよ。チュッ！
I love you all. *Kiss*!
ではでは、完食！おかゆ！
Well then, finishing my meal! Okayu!